http://www.stpatricksday.ie/privacy-policy

×
Privacy Policy
This privacy policy recognises our obligations under the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) which comes into effect on 25 May 2018.
Who We Are
St. Patrick’s Festival is a registered charity, charity number 11729 and is company limited by guarantee, not having a share capital. The principal aim of St. Patrick’s Festival, since its inauguration, is to develop a major annual international festival around Ireland’s national holiday.
Types of Data We Collect
When you visit our website you can do so without submitting any personal data. However, if you wish to receive our newsletter, book tickets, purchase merchandise, join our volunteer programme or become a member of our friends scheme you will be asked to register with us. This involves submitting the following:
Name
Address
Phone number
Email address
Credit card details (when applicable).
Credit card details (when applicable).
When applying for access to our Disabled Access area or Special Needs Viewing area you will be asked to provide the following information:
Name
Address
Phone number
Email address
Details of Disability
Emergency contact name and telephone number
When you sign up for our newsletter via our website, your name and email address is stored on Mailchimp.When you sign up or purchase anything else, your information will be stored by our ticketing partner, Ticketsolve and is used to process your order and to provide you with the purchase/service you have requested.
Ticketsolve acts as a data processor on behalf of St. Patrick’s Festival.If you have provided credit card details, these will only be used for the purpose of handling an individual booking or order. When you book tickets, data is shared between Realex (payment gateway) and Ticketsolve (ticketing platform) in order to process the transaction.You will also be asked if you wish to receive information from St. Patrick’s Festival. If you choose to receive information from us, your data will be shared with Mailchimp (our email partner). Your decision to have further communications from us is recorded and adhered to. You can change your preference for communication with St. Patrick’s Festival at any point which will be recorded immediately.Your record on our database system holds the contact details you submitted to us, transactions you’ve made, a record of communications we would have sent to you, and whether or not you have given us permission to contact you. If you would prefer to have your booking history removed from our database, please email info@stpatricksfestival.ie and we will remove it immediately. You can also unsubscribe from receiving mailings you receive from us by clicking ‘unsubscribe’ at the bottom of the email.
St. Patrick’s Festival, Ticketsolve, Mailchimp and Realex have implemented appropriate technological measures to protect against accidental loss, destruction, damage, alteration or disclosure.
For more information, please see their privacy notices here:
Ticketsolve Privacy Noticehttps://www.ticketsolve.com/privacy-policy/
Mailchimp Privacy Noticehttps://mailchimp.com/legal/privacy/
Realex Privacy Noticehttps://www.globalpaymentsinc.com/en-ie/accept-payments/ecommerce/privacy
Why We Collect Data on Our Customers?
Collecting data on our customers informs us on how best to communicate with you and inform you about events. It assists us to present information and special offers regarding St. Patrick’s Festival that we deem may be of interest to you based on your transaction history. This information helps us understand more about who our audiences are and what their preferences may be. This information helps us make decisions around the conduct of our business.
How We Collect Information
Your data is collected in the following ways with your consent:
When you purchase a ticket (or tickets), merchandise or sign up to membership of our Friends Scheme online, by phone or in person from St. Patrick’s Festival Box Office, your name, address, email and contact number will be stored on our Box Office system, Ticketsolve. Please be assured that we do not share your personal details with any other company without your consent.
When you sign up for our e-newsletter, your name, address, email and contact number will be stored.
If you contact us to let us know you want to receive information from St. Patrick’s Festival about upcoming events your name, address data, email and contact number will be stored on our Box Office system, Ticketsolve.
How We Use Your Information and the Legal Basis
We use and share your data where:
You have agreed or explicitly consented to the using of your data in a specific way (you may withdraw your consent at any time)
We use it where necessary in order to provide the product, ticket or service you have requested/purchased.
We use it where necessary because we have to comply with a legal obligation
We use for legitimate interests (which you have the right to object to)
How Your Personal Data is Kept Confidential
We have measures in place that limits the access to your information. Only those employees who need to come into contact with that data, to provide products and services to you, will do so. Our database system has strict security measures in place and all activity on your record is password protected.
Cookies
St. Patrick’s Festival makes use of ‘cookies’ which are small text files placed on your computer or mobile device that enable us to track certain information relating to your use of the St. Patrick’s Festival’s website.
Cookies allow a site to know if your computer or device has visited that site before. Cookies can then be used to help understand how the site is being used, help you navigate between pages efficiently, help remember your preferences, and generally improve your browsing experience.
When you use the St. Patrick’s Festival website we use Google Analytics to collect standard internet log information and details of visitor behaviour patterns. We do this to find out things such as the number of visitors to the various parts of our website, types of devices used and the length of time on web pages.You may be able to configure your web browser to prevent the use of cookies but this may result in the disabling of certain functionalities and features of our website.The table below explains the cookies we use and why:-
Cookie Name & Purpose
exp_last_visit:Sets the date-time that the user last visited the site, and is set for both guests and logged in users. If not set, is automatically set to 10 years ago. Affects guests and logged in users.exp_tracker:Tracks the last 5 pages viewed by the user, and is used primarily for redirection after logging in etc. Affects guests and logged in users.exp_last_activity:Every time the state is updated (the page reloaded) the last activity is set to the current datetime. Used to determine expiry. This is essential for logged in users, but not for guests - it is set for both.exp_sessionid:A uniquely generated ID that corresponds to the session_id column in the exp_session table. Used when cookie and session are set as the session type. Used only for logged in members.exp_uniqueid:Matches the unique_id field in the exp_members table. Randomly generated by the functions class at registration. Used only for logged in members.exp_userhash:The encrypted password of the currently logged in user. Set if you choose the cookies and session ID method for sessions (cs in your config.) Used only for logged in members.exp_anon:A flag set by the user to determine if they are listed in the online users.exp_expiration:Determines the length of the session for a logged in user. There are two options for this cookie: if the user has selected remember me then it is set to 1 year, and if not then it’s set to the datetime that the user logged in. Used only for logged in members.__utmt:Used to throttle request rate.__utma:Used to distinguish users and sessions. The cookie is created when the javascript library executes and no existing __utma cookies exists. The cookie is updated every time data is sent to Google Analytics.__utmb:Used to determine new sessions/visits. The cookie is created when the javascript library executes and no existing __utmb cookies exists. The cookie is updated every time data is sent to Google Analytics.__utmc:Not used in ga.js. Set for interoperability with urchin.js. Historically, this cookie operated in conjunction with the __utmb cookie to determine whether the user was in a new session/visit__utmz:Stores the traffic source or campaign that explains how the user reached your site. The cookie is created when the javascript library executes and is updated every time data is sent to Google Analytics.Google Analytics
We use Google Analytics to determine how popular components of our website are, to determine if you have been to the website before and to securely and anonymously record the value of any purchases you make on our website. Google analytics sets cookies which will stay active for a number of years and identify on your computer that you have visited our website.
These cookies can be identified by their prefix of __u…. You can opt out of being tracked by Google Analytics across all websites you visit by installing a browser plugin at http://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=en.
How to Control Cookies
You can control and/or delete cookies as you wish – for details, see aboutcookies.org. You can delete all cookies that are already on your computer and you can set most browsers to prevent them from being placed. If you do this, however, you may have to manually adjust some preferences every time you visit a site and some services and functionalities may not work.
Record Retention Periods
Type of Data / Record /Retention PeriodCustomer DataCustomer Data on TicketsolveRemoved after 3 years of inactivity|Customer Data on MailchimpRemoved after 3 years of inactivityPersonnelFinancial/accounts records7 yearsAudit reports/End of year financial statements7 yearsTax records7 yearsHealth & Safety Records10 yearsStaff records7 years (after termination of employment)Recruitment (records and interview notes from unsuccessful applicants)12 monthsAccess to your Personal Data (Subject Access Requests)
You are entitled to view, amend or delete the personal information that we hold. Please email your request to info@stpatricksfestival.ie. For security reasons we will ask you to provide proof of identification.You have the right to rectify or delete inaccuracies in your personal data and to object to the processing of your personal data. You also have the right to withdraw consent for us to hold your personal data at any time, where the legal basis for processing is consent.
We will deal with any subject access requests within 30 days. There will be no charge for any reasonable ‘Subject Access Requests’.
Contact Information
Address:St. Patrick’s FestivalInternet House,26 Temple Bar,Dublin 2,D02 E838
Telephone Number: 01 6040090Email: info@stpatricksfestival.ie
This Privacy Policy will be reviewed and updated from time to time. This version was adopted on 14th May, 2018.
This website uses cookies to ensure you get the best experience on our website.
Got It!More info
